ALI YAZDI

Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran ma.yazdi75@gmail.com • ma.yazdi75@aut.ac.ir • (+98) 912 037 1375 • aliyazdi.tech

ABOUT ME

I have been working as a Flutter developer and mobile team leader for two years. I am a CS graduate who interests in using Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering in my work experiences. I am an open-source advocate who helps developers to solve their problems in development. I am looking for a better opportunity and willing to relocate to a new country.

WORK **EXPERIENCE**

Mate Machine Inc., North Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada - Remote

Jun 2020 - Present

• Working as a flutter developer team leader to launch the application in three months.

Tarafdari, Tehran, Iran

Mar 2019 – May 2020

Flutter, Drupal, Laravel, MySQL

Working as a mobile application team leader at one of the most popular sport social media.

- R&D about Flutter framework and migrating the android application to Flutter application includes multimedia content, live score matches, and sports TV streaming with live chat on the socket.
- We could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to the flutter.

EDUCATION

Amirkabir University of Technology, (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran

- Bachelor of Engineering (BSc.) in Computer Engineering, Software, Ranked 2nd in Iran. Sep 2015 – Jan 2020
 - Thesis: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
 - Adviser: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati

Adab High School. Tehran, Iran

■ Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

Sep 2011 - Jun 2014

HONORS & AWARDS

■ First Place in the 12th Iran Web and Mobile Festival (IWMF)

• For the Best Sport Mobile Application among 7k applications

Feb 2020

Most installed sport application in Iran

May 2020

• In my first job, we could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to the flutter

In Nation-Wide University Entrance Exam among all Iranian Student of Physics and Mathematics

■ Ranked in top 0.2% among more than 180K participants

Jul 2015

- Qualified for the Second Round of Olympiad among more than 70K participants In the Iranian Physics Olympiad and Mathematical Olympiad

Jul 2013

PUBLICATIONS

MEDIUM

- [1] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 1)", Using Software Engineering methods to design and build a fully responsive and adaptive mobile, desktop, and web application, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.
- [2] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 2)", Designing and building the Flutter application structure using the Bloc pattern in the micro-service architecture, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.
- [3] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 3)", Designing and building the Flutter application data models and backend using the Build value and Bloc pattern, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

■ The Flutter Protfolio Application, Flutter

▲ 🐧 🌐

• Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform.

■ The Flutter Gallery Application, Flutter



- Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform using micro-service architecture.
- The Flutter Media Notification Plugin, Java, Flutter
 - Designing and Building a Flutter Plugin that helps developers to show their media notification and control streaming media beyond their Flutter application.
- The Location-Based Recommendation System, Django, Django Rest Framework, Scikit-learn, Flutter
 - Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System with Djando and Flutter.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning
- Software Engineering

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligent and Robotics Lab, Amirkabir University of Technology,

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

- Undergraduate Research Student, Science Department
 - · Project: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
 - Supervisors: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati
 - Focus: Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Data Analytics

LANGUAGES

- Persian: Native language
- English: Fluent, working proficiency

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

Dart, Python, Java, C/C++, PHP, Assembly

Mobile Development

Flutter, Android

Database Systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL

Operating System

Linux (Ubuntu)

■ Web Development

Django, Django Rest Framework

Other

Microcontroller Programming, Bash Scripting

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Programming Languages, racket

• NUMEX-Interpreter: Designing a simple interpreter NUMEX programming language with Racket.

■ **Information Security**, python

• My-Security-Course: Encryption with MD5, SHA256, DES, working with cryptool software nmap and using ms08_067 exploitand.

■ Computer Networks, python

 DNS-UDP-TCP-Proxy: A python proxy that receives HTTP packets on UDP then sends them on TCP with DNS server.

■ Microprocessor & Assembly Language, C

• Digital-Watch-with-LCD: A digital watch with LCD and alarm using microcontroller ATMEGA16.

■ Data Structure & Algorithms, Java

• Finite-State-Machine: Creating four types of data structure and searching using AVL-tree, balance-TST, trie-tree and hash.

Advanced Computer Programmings, Java

• Planet-vs-Zombies: A 2d game similar to Plant vs Zombies game using java object oriented programming.

[*Last Update on 2021-01-14*] • [Clone me on [7]]